XIAOXU ZHOU

- **♀** 15 Union Street, CBD, Auckland, New Zealand
- ☑ zhouxxu1985@gmail.com
- **C** 0210768411
- http://www.zhouxiaoxu.com

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Hi, this is Dan. I have 8 years of work experience (4 years front-end + 4 Years Back-end). My strong capabilities with creating visually stunning responsive web pages and interfaces make me a valuable team member. I am self-motivated and have excellent time management skills, allowing for fast completion of web site projects. I'm certain you will be impressed by the skills I can offer as a Full Stack Web Developer.

Front-end: JavaScript(4 Years+), Backbone.js(2 Years+), React (1 Year+), jQuery. Dozens of front-end libs like lodash, Moment etc. Back-end: Java(3 Year), Node.js(1 Year), Restful API, SQL databases(Oracle, Mysql, DB2), NoSQL databases(MongoDB). Tools: Webpack, Grunt, Git.

DevOps: configured and maintained web servers through AWS, GoogleCloud, Docker, Jenkins.

See my portfolio to find more http://www.zhouxiaoxu.com

WORK HISTORY

E-Site

Auckland, New Zealand Jan 2020 - Present

Freelancer

Auckland, New Zealand Nov 2019 - Dec 2019

IBM

Dalian, China Aug 2012 - Aug 2018

Full-Stack Developer

I am working as a part-time Full Stack Developer in my friend's company and developed an Inventory Management System that allows users to track the IT assets, orders as well as packages, and users' information from scratch.

- Created restful API endpoints including Authentication, IT Assets, Orders, Suppliers and Packages modules with Node.js, Express, Mongoose, and MongoDB.
- Testing API endpoints using postman.
- Built the admin platform for managing IT Assets, Orders, Packages, and Users.
- Implemented complex UI components with Reactjs and SCSS.
- Built CI/CD pipeline with Jenkins on GoogleCloud.

Freelance Web Developer

Worked as a freelancer in my spare time after my graduation from EIT and built several websites on my own from scratch.

- Built and maintained multiple wordpress websites.
- Built and maintained a successful wooCommerce site for a small brand, helping increase sales and revenue.
- Refine and re-develop several custom plugins and themes based on client's designs and requirements.
- Optimized several WordPress websites, helping to reduce page load speeds and improve PageSpeed scores.

Senior Application Developer

Worked as a Senior Application Developer and created several applications for internal use.

- Created and maintained a large SAP called YourlBM (in Backbone.js and jQuery) that allows 400,000 IBMers to access IBM resources like "News", "Media", "E-learning", "Polls" and so on.
- Create dozens of flexible and reusable javascript components in YourIBM project.
- Improved the UX by creating several DnD-based components in YourlBM project.
- Integrated various third party APIs including Messages, Files, Communities and E-Learning to use and manipulate data in YourlBM project.
- Created a backend server to provide restful API endpoints including JWT Auth, Comments, Likes, Users and Proxy modules with Java, Spring, Jersey, DB2.
- Create several modules in an Event management system projects using HTML, Scss, jQuery, PHP and Mysql.

iSoftstone

Dalian, China Nov 2010 - Aug 2012

Neusoft

Dalian, China Oct 2009 - Nov 2011

Java developer

Entered the project as a Java developer. Six months later, I was promoted to be the team leader, because of my professional and responsible attitude towards the work.

- Created and maintained a backend server called Bulk Utility Tool that can process 20,000 broadband orders at the same time from upstream using Java, Camel, Spring, Mybatis, Oracle, Quartz
- Reporting team's work status to manager
- Functional testing

Junior Java Developer

Worked as a Junior Developer. My database skills improved a lot in this project because I wrote hundreds of SQL.

- Create a "Task Management System" which tracks staff daily work using Java, Struts, Spring, JSP, Oracle.
- Wrote JSP, Servlets, and SQL to add functionality.

QUALIFICATIONS

Eastern Institute of Technology

Auckland, New Zealand 2019 Postgraduate Diploma in IT

REFEREES

Referees available on request.